SR. DIRECTOR

Executive Profile

High-performing leader and collaborative business partner with extensive technology and business expertise. Strong record of strategic innovation, enhancing products and services to deliver top-line value while optimizing and automating operations to maximize bottom-line results. Reputation for designing and maintaining quality solutions with high availability, reliability and performance. Track record of building strong technology teams by recruiting, developing and retaining top talent with strong orientation towards outstanding customer service. Legacy of delivering high-impact projects producing outstanding business results. Recognized for enhancing relationships with clients, personal accountability and ability to communicate at all levels of the enterprise. SELECTED CAREER ACHIEVEMENTS Following multiple acquisitions, inherited under-performing legacy IT systems, many with functional overlap with existing systems. After conducting comprehensive analysis, formulated and executed strategy to consolidate, virtualize and standardize several systems, reducing overall operational expense by 40% and improving system availability and performance to meet or exceed Service Level Agreement targets. Established and maintained quality, security standards and compliance controls on information resources year-over-year, including PCI, HIPAA, SSAE 16 and ISO 27001. As primary System Owner, provided key leadership in securing FedRAMP certification for Verizon Terremark Cloud IaaS platform. Directed information technology teams of varying sizes and maturity. Most recently, managed six teams of 180 people in both domestic (USA) and international locations (India, Peru, Belgium.) Experienced in planning and managing technology budgets during all business cycles: startup, high growth, downturn, acquisition integration and business transformation. Managed capital and expense budgets of up to \$100M, supporting enterprise strategies and annual revenues in excess of \$1.5 billion.

Skill Highlights

- Management: * IT strategic planning, delivery and governance * IT startup/turnaround/restructuring
- Driving customer satisfaction and shareholder value * Leading and motivating talented people and collaborative teams
- IT Solutions: * Enterprise and solutions architecture * Infrastructure availability, performance and capacity management
- Process Improvement: * Enterprise policies, processes, procedures * Process re-engineering and transformation
- Systems automation and integration
- Security: * Information security management and compliance

Professional Experience

Sr. Director

January 2011 to Current Pfizer i1/4 Durham, NC

- Upon acquisition of Terremark by Verizon, selected to integrate systems management functions for legacy Verizon business units for Colocation, Managed Services and Cloud with those of Terremark.
- Overall portfolio increased to more than 240 distinct systems across 50 data centers, with a global team of 180 systems engineers, administrators, developers and supporting staff.
- Led systems integration and consolidation between Terremark and Verizon business units, resulting in \$10M annualized cost savings.
- Successfully achieved FedRAMP certification for Enterprise Cloud Federal Edition, securing \$84M+ annualized revenue stream
- Virtualized 70% of overall systems portfolio, reducing capital and operational expenditure outlays by 15%.
- Extended offshore team to include select IT operations and administration functions for follow-the-sun support model at 40% labor cost savings.
- Initiated and managed Vulnerability Management Program across all Verizon Cloud Services infrastructure reducing month-over-month external vulnerability exposure by 95%.
- Oversaw development of automated OS patching process for VMWare ESX, enabling seamless, zero-downtime monthly updates with 80% reduction in labor investment.
- Advanced regulatory and compliance adherence across portfolio including SSAE 16, ISO270001, PCI, HIPPA and FedRAMP.
- Served as Verizon Lean Six Sigma Champion on multiple process optimization projects and charter member of Verizon Cloud Information Security Council, authoring several policy and process documents.

Sr. Manager

January 2003 to January 2011 Panera Bread Co

- IT & Operational Support Services acquired Data Return, LLC, in 2007), Dallas, TX Following acquisition of divine Managed Services by Saratoga Partners, relaunch of Data Return, LLC, and subsequent acquisition by Terremark, responsibilities extended to include Corporate IT, Network Engineering and Information Security departments.
- Assumed responsibilities for engineering and operational management of virtualization-based Managed Services Cloud service offerings.
- Built Security Operations team and Information Security Council to support growing security, governance and compliance requirements for \$4.8M Payment Card Industry (PCI) customer base.
- Deployed Managed and Cloud Services into Terremark domestic and international data centers enabling 30% revenue growth.
- Eliminated non-strategic and redundant systems, achieving \$2M annualized cost-savings in OS, database and software licensing fees.
- Reorganized IT Operations Teams to align with ITIL functions for Incident, Problem, Change, Release and Capacity Management, increasing efficiency by 20% and reducing average incident rate by 25%.
- Introduced Agile Operations / DevOps concepts to IT Operations Teams, resulting in improved quality, time-to-market of new features and functionality and deployment time reduction of 75%.

Manager

January 1999 to January 2003 Monitoring Services Divine, Inc

• acquired Data Return Corp.

- in 2001), Dallas, TX Implemented and managed 24x7 best-of-breed Network Operations Center for startup Managed Services provider, Data Return.
- Upon acquisition of Data Return by divine, selected to consolidate and streamline NOC operations and related monitoring systems across Data Return and four other divine Managed Services' acquisitions.
- Developed and implemented 24x7 monitoring and systems management strategy, including technology & toolset selection, architecture, implementation and ongoing operational management exceeding Service Level Agreement availability targets of 99.999%.
- Consolidated 24x7-NOC monitoring team with customer-facing Service Desk resulting in \$1M annualized savings.
- Eliminated over 250 non-strategic and redundant IT systems, achieving \$1.5M annualized cost savings in OS and software licensing fees.
- Developed & documented policies, processes and procedures, resulting in 25% reduction in rework and increased customer satisfaction.

Education

Master of Science: Electrical Engineering Computer Engineering Oklahoma State University Electrical Engineering Computer Engineering Bachelor of Science: Business, Finance Oklahoma City University Business, Finance Stati

acquisitions, streamline, Agile, automation, Council, Critical Thinking, customer satisfaction, database and software, Decision Making, delivery, Driving, features, Hewlett-Packard, Information Security, ISO, ITIL, Leadership, market, Enterprise, Network Engineering, Network, OS, optimization, PCI, policies, Process re-engineering, processes, Process Improvement, quality, Six Sigma, Service Level Agreement, strategy, strategic, strategic planning, sun, systems integration, systems management